Guide to the Royal Development Company (Trinity Mine) Records 1896-1946
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
Royal Development Company (Trinity Mine) Records
1896-1946
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0019royaldev
Royal Development Company
13 Linear Ft. 12 Boxes; 9 Oversize Folders
The records of the Royal Development Company document the use of material and labor at the Royal Development Company's Trinity Mine in Washinton's Chiwawa mining district. The records reflect an emphasis on the day-to-day operations of the mine and include numerous maps and plans regarding the mine and the surrounding area.
The Royal Development Company of Leavenworth, Washington, gained its articles of incorporation on July 3rd, 1917. Trinity Mine, a subsidiary of the Royal Development Company, produced mainly copper ore mined from the Chiwawa district. The Chiwawa district includes the drainage of the Little Wenatchee, White, and Chiwawa Rivers. While the mainstay of the mine was copper silver, gold and tungsten were also found as byproducts. In 1929, about 2,500 feet of mining work was done with a workforce of 80 employees. In support of operations at the mine, the Royal Development Company operated a large and completely equipped lumber camp including a 250-500 ton mill, water power development, sawmill, and town site with 20 million feet of timber available. In early 1930 a flotation mill was erected and by 1936 the mine produced more than 10,000 tons of copper ore. However, in 1937 operations began to slow and the mine produced only 5,825 tons. As costs increased and the returns did not, operations were slowed. The company was forced into receivership in the early 1940s and the workforce was reduced to a night watchman who lived there year round. The Royal Development Company dissolved on June 28th, 1948.
The records of the Royal Development Company document the operations of the Trinity Mine, located in the Chiwawa mining district in Chelan County, Washington. The records span the period 1923-1946 with the bulk of materials dated pre-1936. Timesheets and payroll records, daily, shift, and mill reports, supply and tally books, maps, and plans document the manpower and material required for copper production. Accident reports document the high number of miners' injuries. There are also supply and tally books covering material stocked and bought at the company store. These records are complete and cover the period between 1923 and 1933. Also included in the records are manuals and catalogs from manufacturers. The collection does not contain internal company correspondence or organizational records.
The maps and plans of the collection comprise an organizational chart of the company, daily reports of operations, profile and topographic maps of the mine and surrounding area, and several mechanical drawings of the equipment used at the mine.
The collection was found scattered on the floors throughout the Trinity Mine complex in the mid-1970s and shows deterioration from lack of adequate storage conditions.. Due to this factor most of the material is stained and fragile. The contextual information is still available, however, and can be used to glean insights into the life and times of early 20th century miners and mining camps of Central Washington.
The collection is organized in accordance with the following series arrangement:
Series I: Reports, 1923-1946
Series II: Inventories, 1923-1941
Series III: Correspondence and Construction File, 1923-1940
Series IV: Manuals and Catalogs, 1923-1945
Series V: Maps, Plans, and Oversize Material, 1896-1930
Subseries 1: Maps, 1914-1930
Subseries 2: Plans, 1896-1930
Subseries 3: Oversize Material, 1929-1930
The collection is open to the public.
The Royal Development Company (Trinity Mine) Records were donated by Nigel Adams to the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies in 1977.
Harold Culver and W.A. Broughton, Tungsten Resources in Washington Washington State, Division of Geology, Bulletin No. 34. Olympia, WA. 1945.
Florin, Lambert. Washington Ghost Towns. Western Ghost town Series. Superior Publishing Co. Seattle WA.
Marshall T. Huntting, Inventory of Mineral Properties in Chelan County, WA., Washington State Department of Conservation and Development, Division of Geology, Report of Investigations #9, Olympia, WA. 1943.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Royal Development Co.
Trinity Mine; Chelan County--Washington (State)
Royal Development Company; Trinity Mine.; Mines and mineral resources--Washington (State)--Chelan County.; Copper mines and mining--Washington (State)--Chelan County.; Logging--Washington (State)--Chelan County.; Lumber Camps--Washington (State)--Chelan County.; Sawmills.
Washington (State); Maps; Forestry and Forestry Products; Logging; Mines and Mineral Resources
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Reports, 1923-1946; Series I
  - Daily Reports of Operations at Trinity Camp
    - Daily Reports, 1931 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Daily Reports, 1936 January – June (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Daily Reports, 1936 July– December (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Timesheets, 1923 April– August (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Timesheets, 1923 September– December (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Timesheets, 1923 January– 1924 June (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Timesheets, 1924 July – August (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Timesheets, 1924 September – December (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Timesheets, 1925 January – July (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Timesheets, 1927 January (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Timesheets, 1929 September – October (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Timesheets, 1929 November – December (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Timesheets, 1931 July – August (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Timesheets, 1932 January– August (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Timesheets, 1933 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Timesheets, 1934 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Timesheets, 1936 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Timesheets, 1938 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Timesheets, 1939 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Timesheets, 1942 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Timesheets, 1943 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Timesheets, 1944 March; 1944 December (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Timesheets, 1945 March (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Shift Report and Cost Sheets, 1924 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Shift Report and Cost Sheets, 1925 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Shift Report and Cost Sheets, 1926 January– June (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Shift Report and Cost Sheets, 1926 July – December (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Shift Report and Cost Sheets, 1927 January– June (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Shift Report and Cost Sheets, 1927 June – December (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Shift Report and Cost Sheets, 1928 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Shift Report and Cost Sheets, 1929 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Daily Reports for Day and Night Shifts, 1936 January – October (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Daily Reports for Day and Night Shifts, 1936 November – December (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Daily Reports for Day and Night Shifts, 1937 January – August (Box-folder 3/21)
  - Distribution of Labor (incomplete), 1924-1944 (Box-folder 3/22)
  - Distribution of Labor and Payroll Reports, 1923-1946 (Box 4)
  - Powerhouse Reports, 1924 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Powerhouse Reports, 1925 (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Powerhouse Reports, 1926 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Powerhouse Reports, 1927 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Powerhouse Reports, 1928 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Powerhouse Reports, 1930 January – June (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Powerhouse Reports, 1930 July – December (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Powerhouse Reports, 1931 January – June (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Powerhouse Reports, 1931 July – December (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Powerhouse Reports (incomplete), 1932-1936 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Daily Logging Reports, 1923 August (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Daily Sawmill Reports, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Daily Log Records, 1923 July– September; 1924;; 1930 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Daily Lumber Records, 1923 August – September; 1930 July (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Layoff Request Forms, circa 1930 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Accident and Injury Reports, 1928 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Unidentified employee (?) lists, 1928; 1931 (Box-folder 7/5)
- Inventories, 1923-1945; Series II
  - Supply Inventory, circa 1938 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Food Supply Reports, 1929 July; 1929 October – November (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Commissary Supplies
    - A-C, 1927-1940 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - D-M, 1927-1940 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - N-R, 1927-1940 (Box-folder 8/2)
    - S-Z, 1927-1940 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Road House and Boardinghouse, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Tally Books, 1923 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Tally Books, 1924 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Tally Books, 1925 March; 1925 May;; 1925 July (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Tally Books, 1925 August-September (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Tally Books, 1926 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Tally Books, 1927 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Tally Books, 1928 February-June (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Tally Books, 1928 July-September (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Tally Books, 1928 October-December (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Tally Books, 1929 March-May (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Tally Books, 1929 June-July; 1929 September-October (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Tally Books, 1929 October-December (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Tally Books, 1930 February-May (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Tally Books, 1930 July-October (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Tally Books, 1931 April-May; 1931 August- 1932 January (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Tally Books, 1932 January – 1933 November (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Tally Books, Undated (Box-folder 11/4)
- Correspondence and Construction File, 1923-1940; Series III
  - Correspondence and Construction Information, 1923-1940 (Box-folder 11/5)
- Manuals and Catalogs, 1923-1930; Series IV
  - Equipment Catalogs and Manuals, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 11/6)
  - Equipment Catalogs and Manuals, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 11/7)
- Maps, Plans and Oversized Materials, 1896-1930; Series V
  - Maps, 1914-1930; Subseries 1
    - Blueprint: Leavenworth No. 1 Chelan County, WA, 1914 (Folder-map 1/1)
    - Contour Map Royal Development Co. Mill, 1930 (Folder-map 1/2)
    - Levels for Mill Site, Undated (Folder-map 1/3)
    - Topographic Map (Unknown Location), Undated (Folder-map 1/4)
    - St. Francis and Leprechaun Tunnels, Undated (Folder-map 1/5)
    - Topographical Map (Unknown Location), Undated (Folder-map 1/6)
    - Topographic Map of Proposed Water Supply from Intake on James Creek to Proposed Intake On Alpine Creek, 1924 (Folder-map 1/7)
    - Topographical Map (Unknown Location), Undated (Folder-map 1/8)
    - Brunton Survey for Trinity Road Improvement, Undated (Folder-map 1/9)
    - Pre-Road Survey Trinity to Little Giant, Undated (Folder-map 1/10)
    - Hydraulic Investigation Railroad Creek near Lucerne, Washington Gauging Station Layout, Undated (Folder-map 1/11)
    - Trinity Tunnel Track Levels # 2, Undated (Folder-map 1/12)
    - Trinity Tunnel Track Levels # 3, Undated (Folder-map 1/13)
    - Trinity Tunnel Ventilation Problem, Undated (Folder-map 1/14)
    - Topographic Map of Steam Line Mill, Undated (Folder-map 1/15)
    - Profile of James Creek Power Line, Undated (Folder-map 1/16)
    - Profile of Phelps Creek Power Project, Undated (Folder-map 1/17)
    - Profile of Plumbing, Undated (Folder-map 1/18)
    - Profile of Crushing Unit/ Topographic Map of Mill Site, Undated (Folder-map 1/19)
    - Profiles of Crusher and Mill, 1930 (Folder-map 1/20)
    - Profile of Trinity Tunnel Site, 1924 (Folder-map 1/21)
  - Plans, 1896-1930; Subseries 2
    - Belt Conveyor Rolls, undated (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Cable Bracket Detail, 1928 (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Car Wheels, undated (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Circuits, Connectors, and Connections, 1924; 1926,; 1930 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Compressors, undated (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Crushing Unit, undated (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Gears and Sprockets, 1930 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Installation Drawing, 1928 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Ore Scraper, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 12/9)
    - Ore Chute (underground), undated (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Short Radius Bends, undated (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Sketch showing Grizzlys Set Up Bulldozing Chamber, undated (Box-folder 12/12)
    - Trinity Tunnel, 1930 (Box-folder 12/13)
    - Unidentified Machinery Specifications, undated (Box-folder 12/14)
    - Government Standard Scale Works, Undated (Folder-drawing 2/1)
    - "Little Trammer" Locomotive, Undated (Folder-drawing 2/2)
    - Safety Hoisting Cage, 1913 (Folder-drawing 2/3)
    - Safety Hoisting Cage, 1913 (Folder-drawing 2/4)
    - Assembly 40 H.P. Single Drum Mine Hoist, 1929 (Folder-drawing 2/5)
    - 48" Union Iron Works Carriage Assembly R.H., 1925 (Folder-drawing 2/6)
    - Safety Cross Head for Bucket Hoisting, Undated (Folder-drawing 2/7)
    - Setting Plan for 3 3/4" X 3 3/8" Type "H" 2 Stage Air Compressor - Belt Drive, 1926 (Folder-drawing 2/8)
    - Lubricating Oil Piping Engine to Filter for 1, 2 & 3 Cylinder 14 X 17 Diesel Stat. Engine, 1928 (Folder-drawing 2/9)
    - Exhaust Conduit, 1926 (Folder-drawing 2/10)
    - Type FMQ2 Mtg. - Ward Leonard Rheostat, 1929 (Folder-drawing 2/11)
    - Pipe Connection Plan, 1926 (Folder-drawing 2/12)
    - Foundation Plan 14 X 17 - 6 Cylinder Station Diesel Engine, 1929 (Folder-drawing 2/13)
    - Foundation Plan 200 H.P. "Y" Engine D.C. to 170 K.V. Alternator, 1922 (Folder-drawing 2/14)
    - Semi - Automatic Starter - Reduced Voltage, 1930 (Folder-drawing 2/15)
    - 40 H.P. Single drum Hoist Foundation Plan, 1929 (Folder-drawing 2/16)
    - 10 cubic feet Bottom Dump Bucket, 1930 (Folder-drawing 2/17)
    - Friction Rope Feed, 1907 (Folder-drawing 2/18)
    - Details Friction Rope feed, 1907 (Folder-drawing 2/19)
    - Muller Ore Jig - Sheet 132, 1896 (Folder-drawing 3/1)
    - Muller Ore Jig - Sheet 133, 1896 (Folder-drawing 3/2)
    - Muller Ore Jig - Sheet 134, 1896 (Folder-drawing 3/3)
    - Muller Ore Jig - Sheet 135, 1896 (Folder-drawing 3/4)
    - Muller Ore Jig - Sheet 136, 1896 (Folder-drawing 3/5)
    - Muller Ore Jig - Sheet 139, 1896 (Folder-drawing 3/6)
    - Muller Ore Jig - Sheet 140, 1896 (Folder-drawing 3/7)
    - Part List of 14 H.R. - Hoist, 1929 (Folder-drawing 3/8)
    - Part List of 9 H.R. Special Little Tugger Hoist, 1927 (Folder-drawing 3/9)
    - 9 H.R. - Little Tugger Hoist, 1927 (Folder-drawing 3/10)
    - 14 H.R. - Little Tugger Hoist, 1929 (Folder-drawing 3/11)
    - D.W.G. 769, 1928 (Folder-drawing 3/12)
    - Air Operated Loading Chute, 1929 (Folder-drawing 3/13)
    - Layout of Class "C" Hydrant Shoe, 1930 (Folder-drawing 3/14)
    - 2½” x 14" - 4 Stage Multiplex Vertical Sinking Pump, 1927 (Folder-drawing 3/15)
    - 16 inch Direct Connected Fan, 1928 (Folder-drawing 3/16)
    - The Dorr Classifier, 1927 (Folder-drawing 3/17)
    - Class "C" Hydrant Shoe with Auxiliary Valve, 1930 (Folder-drawing 3/18)
    - 30" Pelton Impulse Turbines, undated (Folder-drawing 3/19)
    - Sleeve and Large Tip, undated (Folder-drawing 3/20)
    - The Dorr Co. intake connection to pump body, 1926 (Folder-drawing 3/21)
    - Dorr Co. Classifier, 1930 (Folder-drawing 3/22)
    - The Dorr Thickener, 1927 (Folder-drawing 3/23)
    - The Dorr Co Filter, 1929 (Folder-drawing 4/1)
    - Standard Diagram for Mine Signals, 1926 (Folder-drawing 4/2)
    - Signal Bell Panel for Engine Stands, 1923 (Folder-drawing 4/3)
    - Switchboard - Crushing Unit, 1930 (Folder-drawing 4/4)
    - Switchboard, 1928 (Folder-drawing 4/5)
    - Lightning Arrestor, 1922 (Folder-drawing 4/6)
    - Generator (Outline) - Sheet 1, 1928 (Folder-drawing 4/7)
    - Generator (Outline) - Sheet 2, 1928 (Folder-drawing 4/8)
    - Generator (Outline) - Sheet 3, 1928 (Folder-drawing 4/9)
    - Cross-section M&T Scale (sheet one), undated (Folder-drawing 4/10)
    - Truss lever M&T Scale (sheet two), undated (Folder-drawing 4/11)
    - Cast-Iron Base, 1921 (Folder-drawing 4/12)
    - Foundation Plan for 20 - 35 H.P. Jr. Electric Hoist, 1925 (Folder-drawing 4/13)
    - Fahrenwald 32" Cell Flo Machine with Structural Steel Frame, 1929 (Folder-drawing 4/14)
    - Speed Regulator Limit Switch Assembly, 1928 (Folder-drawing 4/15)
    - Motor driven Speed Regulator Assembly, 1928 (Folder-drawing 4/16)
    - 45 H.P. Electric Mine Hoist, 1929 (Folder-drawing 4/17)
    - H.P. Electric Mine Hoist, 1929 (Folder-drawing 4/18)
    - 13/16" Shaft Macintosh Flotation Machine, 1930 (Folder-drawing 4/19)
    - 24" Shaft Macintosh Flotation Machine, 1929 (Folder-drawing 4/20)
    - Assembly (Locomotive), undated (Folder-drawing 4/21)
    - General Plan, 1899 (Folder-drawing 4/22)
    - Assembly D68, 1919 (Folder-drawing 4/23)
    - Assembly D68, 1919 (Folder-drawing 4/24)
    - Single Screw Column, 1926 (Folder-drawing 5/1)
    - Mine Hoist Signal Circuit, 1930 (Folder-drawing 5/2)
    - Mine Hoist Signal Circuit, 1925 (Folder-drawing 5/3)
    - Hopper Plates, undated (Folder-drawing 5/4)
    - Toggle Joint Seat, 1930 (Folder-drawing 5/5)
    - Construction Details Fine Grinding Section, 1930 (Folder-drawing 5/6)
    - Single Sheave Block, 1925 (Folder-drawing 5/7)
    - Single Sheave Block, 1925 (Folder-drawing 5/8)
    - Crusher Circuit, 1930 (Folder-drawing 5/9)
    - Truss Plates Detail, 1930 (Folder-drawing 5/10)
    - Conveyor Control Circuit, 1930 (Folder-drawing 5/11)
    - Conveyor Control Circuit, 1930 (Folder-drawing 5/12)
    - Parts for 4 1/2" Special Column Bar, 1929 (Folder-drawing 5/13)
    - Details of Plate for Trusses of Crushing Unit, 1930 (Folder-drawing 5/14)
    - Special Gate Valve and Feeder Assembly, 1930 (Folder-drawing 5/15)
    - Geary - Jennings Sample Cutter, 1929 (Folder-drawing 5/16)
    - Revolving Screen, 1917 (Folder-drawing 5/17)
    - Short Radius Bends, Undated (Folder-drawing 5/18)
    - Self - Dumping Skip for Vertical Shaft, Undated (Folder-drawing 5/19)
    - Unidentified Plans, undated (Folder-drawing 5/20 - 5/21)
    - D.F.C. Muffle, Undated (Folder-drawing 5/22)
    - Layout of Gravel Screening and Loading Plant, 1930 May 3 (Folder-drawing 6/1)
    - Wheel End Door – Ore Car for Talache Mines Inc., 1922 September 1 (Folder-drawing 6/2)
    - No. 3 Conveyor (fragile), undated (Folder-drawing 6/3)
    - No. 4 Conveyor (fragile), undated (Folder-drawing 6/4)
    - No. 5 Conveyor (fragile), undated (Folder-drawing 6/5)
    - No. 5 Conveyor, undated (Folder-drawing 6/6)
    - No. 6. Conveyor, undated (Folder-drawing 6/7)
    - 30’ Belt Conveyor, undated (Folder-drawing 6/8)
    - Picking Ore Car, 1929 August 17 (Folder-drawing 6/9)
    - 21 cu. ft. Skip with Cage, 1915 July 24 (Folder-drawing 6/10)
    - Underground Battery Charging Station, 1930 July 11 (Folder-drawing 6/11)
    - Underground Battery Charging Station, 1930 July 11 (Folder-drawing 6/12)
    - Detail of Gate, 1930 August 10 (Folder-drawing 6/13)
    - Detail of Gate, 1930 August 11 (Folder-drawing 6/14)
    - Roof Trusses for Concentrating Units, 1930 June 30 (Folder-drawing 6/15)
    - Fine Grinding and Concentrating Unit, 1930 January 25 (Folder-drawing 6/16)
    - Fine Grinding and Concentrating Unit, 1930 January 25 (Folder-drawing 6/17)
    - Fine Grinding and Concentrating Unit, 1930 April 15 (Folder-drawing 6/18)
    - Fine Grinding and Concentrating Unit, 1930 June 7 (Folder-drawing 6/19)
    - Section Details of Fine Ore Bin and Concentrating Units, 1930 January 25 (Folder-drawing 6/20)
    - Section Details of Fine Ore Bin and Concentrating Units, 1930 April 9 (Folder-drawing 6/21)
    - External View of Fine Grinding and Concentrating Mill, 1930 June 18 (Folder-drawing 6/22)
    - External View of Fine Grinding and Concentrating Mill (damaged), 1930 June 18 (Folder-drawing 6/23)
    - External View of Fine Grinding and Concentrating Mill (damaged), undated (Folder-drawing 6/24)
    - Construction Details Fine Grinding Section, 1930 January 14 (Folder-drawing 6/25)
    - Detail of 15 cu. ft Bucket Crosshead and Chute, 1929 March 19 (Folder-drawing 6/26)
    - Plan of Crushing Unit, 1930 February 6 (Folder-drawing 6/27)
    - Truss Diagrams for Fine Grinding Section, 1930 January 8 (Folder-drawing 6/27)
    - Plan of Crushing Unit, 1930 April 5 (Folder-drawing 6/28)
    - Plan of Crushing Unit, 1930 May 15 (Folder-drawing 6/29)
    - Plan of Crushing Unit, undated (Folder-drawing 6/30)
    - Detailed Sections thru Crushing Unit, 1930 April 10 (Folder-drawing 6/31)
    - External View – Crushing Unit (Fragment), 1930 February 11 (Folder-drawing 6/32)
    - Construction Details Fine Crushing Section, 1930 August 14 (Folder-drawing 6/33)
    - Roof Trusses of Crushing Unit, 1930 June 15 (Folder-drawing 6/34)
    - Section of Crushing Unit, 1930 April 15 (Folder-drawing 6/35)
    - Section of Crushing Unit, 1930 April 15 (Folder-drawing 6/36)
    - Flow Sheet of Preliminary Plan of Crushing Section, undated (Folder-drawing 6/37)
    - No. 1 Apron Conveyor, 1930 July 14 (Folder-drawing 7/1)
    - Rotary Car Dump, 1930 September 8 (Folder-drawing 7/2)
    - Rotary Car Dump, 1930 September 8 (Folder-drawing 7/3)
    - 42” Steel Frame Fahrenwald Flotation Machine Assembly, circa 1929 (Folder-drawing 7/4)
    - Flotation Cell, 1930 August 2 (Folder-drawing 7/5)
    - Cage Details B.C. Silver Mines Ltd., 1926 November 30 (Folder-drawing 7/6)
    - H.S.B.C.-H-S-I, 1929 October 18 (Folder-drawing 7/7)
    - Assembly 4.0” x 16’ Screen Clifton Applegate, undated (Folder-drawing 7/8)
    - Assembly of 27 cu. ft. skip and cage, 1929 March 25 (Folder-drawing 7/9)
    - Fine Ore Bin, undated (Folder-drawing 7/10)
    - Detail of Fine Ore Bin, undated (Folder-drawing 7/11)
    - Detail of Coarse Ore Bin & Filter Section Truss, 1930 June 27 (Folder-drawing 7/12)
    - Coarse Ore Bins, 1930 July 7 (Folder-drawing 7/13)
    - Details of Oreways, undated (Folder-drawing 7/14)
    - Preliminary Planner for Concentrator (damaged – partial plan), undated (Folder-drawing 7/15)
    - Sectional Views of Crushing unit, undated (Folder-drawing 7/16)
    - Details of Penstock Connections, 1928 August 23 (Folder-drawing 7/17)
    - Ore Scraper, 1925 March 23 (Folder-drawing 7/18)
    - Combined Skip and Cage for Shaft Sinking, 1929 March 7 (Folder-drawing 7/19)
    - Assembly and Detail Drawing of Loading Platform, 1923 June 22 (Folder-drawing 7/20)
    - Detail of Chutes, undated (Folder-drawing 7/21)
    - Detail of Chutes, 1930 August 7 (Folder-drawing 7/22)
    - Detail of Chutes, 1930 August 12 (Folder-drawing 7/23)
    - Special Gate Valve and Feeder Assembly (Fragile), undated (Folder-drawing 7/24)
    - Double Lip Bagley Scraper, 1921 June 13 (Folder-drawing 7/25)
    - Belt Conveyor, undated (Folder-drawing 7/26)
    - Blake Crusher Surge Bin and Shaker Screen, 1930 July 12 (Folder-drawing 7/27)
    - Conveyor (“#10139”), undated (Folder-drawing 7/28)
    - Blower, 1924 August 27 (Folder-drawing 7/29)
    - 32” Cell Union Iron Works Gravity Flotation Machine, 1928 February 18 (Folder-drawing 7/30)
    - 19 cu. ft. skip with cage, 1915 August 24 (Folder-drawing 7/31)
    - Detail of Coarse Ore Bin Filter Section Trusses, 1930 June 27 (Folder-drawing 7/32)
    - Flow Sheet, 1930 September 11 (Folder-drawing 7/33)
    - Diesel Engine Foundation, 1930 July 16 (Folder-drawing 7/34)
    - 150 Level, undated (Folder-drawing 7/35)
    - Pipe Connection Plan, 1929 September 28 (Folder-drawing 7/36)
    - Conical Ball Mill, 1930 May 27 (Folder-drawing 7/37)
    - Concentrate Bin, 1936 June (Folder-drawing 7/38)
    - Heating Plant, undated (Folder-drawing 7/39)
    - Boiler Room, undated (Folder-drawing 7/40)
    - Floor Plan, undated (Folder-drawing 8/1)
    - Oil Storage Tank Foundation, 1930 June 5 (Folder-drawing 8/2)
    - Square Set Timbering, 1930 July 7 (Folder-drawing 8/3)
    - Kewanee Boiler, undated (Folder-drawing 8/4)
    - Powder Magazine, 1924 February 27 (Folder-drawing 8/5)
    - Wood Tank Phelps Creek Unit Trinity Power Project, 1926 April 10 (Folder-drawing 8/6)